Alexandra Hernandez

San Diego, California 92126 (951) 595-9228 arh003@ucsd.edu

alexavndra.github.io, linkedin.com/in/alexavndrarh, github.com/alexavndra

UC San Diego undergraduate majoring in Cognitive Sciences, and minoring in Computer Sciences. Specializing in machine learning, programming, APIs, algorithm development, data analysis, and frontend and backend development.

EXPERIENCE

UC San Diego Extended Studies La Jolla, CA

Computer Science and Engineering Python Tutor

June 2023-Present

Helping students at the UC San Diego Extended Studies program learn Python and Object Oriented Programming principles. Interacted via weekly lab hours and tested Stepik exercises prior to release (for preparation).

Qualcomm Institute UC San Diego La Jolla, CA WordPress Developer

Website design and consultation for Qualcomm Institute's TREDS Program. Using LMS applications, Figma, Google Cloud API, HTML, and CSS, as well as WordPress and PHP. Implemented digital programs, collect and analyze data and research for supervisors. Work with SEO concept and tools for main website.

Sept 2022-Present

UC San Diego Cognitive Sciences Department La Jolla, CA COGS1 Instructional Assistant

Jan 2023-Mar 2023

Worked with Professor Mary ET Boyle in Introduction to Cognitive Sciences. Created section assignments and quiz questions and led two discussion sections. Managed class communications and the IA/TA Google application.

Qualcomm Institute UC San Diego

WordPress Developer

La Jolla, CA

May 2022-Worked on frontend design, analytics, and implementation for WalkMe program at UC San Diego. Used Sept 2022 ¡Query, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and CMS. Implementing designs for university websites and programs. Prototyped and tested implementations for UC San Diego. Used JIRA and HTTPS for managing software.

Utilized automation with content via WalkMe and DAP. In compliance with 508 accessibilities.

EDUCATION

La Jolla, CA UC SAN DIEGO

Bachelor of Science in Cognitive Sciences-Machine Learning & Neural Computation. Minoring in Computer Science

September 2021–Present

Honors: Marshall College Provost Honors (FA21, WI22, SP22, FA22).

SKILLS

Experience in Java, Python, MATLAB and Git/GitHub; VSCode, Jupyter, and DataSpell. Basic SQL, Google Cloud API, and HTTPS/XML knowledge. Experience of JIRA (IBM Toolchain Build Tool) and basic Kubernetes knowledge.

Proficiency in web designing with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, and Content Management Systems. Worked with user feedback and design programs such as Figma and Adobe Illustrator; basic knowledge of Sketch. Work with Google Sheets and Docs, Excel and Word.

PROJECTS

Digital Art Keywords: Data science research project that analyzes the relationship between caption keywords and DeviantArt content using Python, specifically DeviantArt API, NumPy, Seaborn, MatPlotLib, and SciPy. Group project via Git workflow/Jupyter.

Astrologify: Console app that uses Spotify API, Python, and Git to create user playlist with given user data. Used VSCode and GitHub.

Reminder App: Desktop program that uses EasyApp UI and Java to create reminders for the user through tasks and lists; incorporates times and dates. Created using NetBeans IDE.

REFERENCES

Francisco Mejia (WalkMe): f4mejia@ucsd.edu

Lesley Copeland (Qualcomm Institute): lcopeland@health.ucsd.edu